(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
開演までしばらくお待ちください
Please wait a while until the performance starts.
愛されたい気も曇ないのに
Even though my desire to be loved isn't clouded
愛される温もりだけは知っていた
I only knew the warmth of being loved
生まれてきたその瞬間から
From the moment I was born
誰かの手求めて生きてきたんだ
I've lived seeking someone's hand
ああ　伸ばした手だけ崩れ落ちた
Ah, only the hand I reached out crumbled away
そんな夜のようなこの思いが
This feeling, like that kind of night
胸にあるんだ　僕も未完成なんだ
Is in my chest; I too am incomplete
終わらない夜には　独りきりの朝には
In the never-ending night, in the lonely morning
隣で笑うように　涙が零れないように
So that I can laugh by your side, so that tears don't spill
孤独に輝いた　独りぼっちの星が
A star shining in solitude, all alone
ここにいるよと叫んで歌になった
Cried out "I'm here" and became a song
誰かがそれを綺麗と言った
Someone called it beautiful
わけもなく泣きたくなるような
Like wanting to cry for no reason
虚しさと寂しさだけを打ち寄せて
Just the emptiness and loneliness wash over me
ああ　火をつけてさ　温め合うんだ
Ah, light a fire and let's warm each other
もう二度と凍えてしまわないように
So that we never freeze again
ねえ　正解とか　間違いとか
Hey, whether it's right or wrong
今は何もわからないけれど
I don't know anything right now
一つだけ確かなのは　私がいるってことだけ
But the only certain thing is that I am here
近付いた分だけ離れていく夢さえ
Even the dreams that drift away the closer I get
今ならその迷い事　笑える気がするから
I feel like I can laugh at those hesitations now
孤独に輝いた　点と点を合わせて
Connecting the dots that shone in solitude
受注販売グッズ
Order-to-order merchandise
独りじゃないと叫んで歌になった
Cried out "I'm not alone" and became a song
誰かがそれを「彗星」と言った
Someone called it a "comet"
あなたの頭上に今も降りかかる
Still falling over your head now
悲しみ溶かす光になりたい
I want to become the light that melts the sadness
胸の痛みも一緒に抱えていくから　教えて
I'll carry the pain in your chest together with you, so tell me
Flower Stand 紹介
Flower Stand Introduction
終わらない夜には　独りきりの朝には
In the never-ending night, in the lonely morning
隣で笑うように　涙が零れないように
So that I can laugh by your side, so that tears don't spill
孤独に輝いた　独りぼっちの星が
A star shining in solitude, all alone
ここにいるよと叫んで歌になった
Cried out "I'm here" and became a song
いつか誰かの夜を照らすように
So that one day it shines on someone's night
照らせるように
So that it can shine
Flower Stand
フラワースタンド紹介
Flower Stand Introduction
だって僕は星を歌う
Because I sing to the stars
感情が歪んで破れてた
My emotions were warped and torn
頑丈な太古の衝動が
Robust ancient impulses
言わなきゃいけない言葉いっぱい
So many words I have to say
あなたの目に映る
Reflected in your eyes
可愛い私
The cute me
この瞬間オンリー望んでた midnight
I've only wanted this moment, midnight
追われるまで
Until I'm chased away
ロマンスは殺した
Romance is dead
足りない 聞かせて今だけは
It's not enough, let me hear it, just for now
アモーレ カモネ 夜に甘えて
Amore, maybe... indulged in the night
無理矢理口付けに意味なんてないの
抑えられない方程式
Forcing a kiss is meaningless,
an uncontrollable equation
Attention
ご来場の皆様へ
To all attendees
マスクの着用にご協力ください
撮影/録音/録画は禁止とさせていただきます
Please cooperate by wearing a mask.
Filming, audio recording, and video recording are prohibited.
真っ白な思い愛お情が
Pure white thoughts and affection
滲んで汚れてた
Were blurred and stained
不器用な太古の対話が
Clumsy ancient dialogue
不条理な言葉いっぱい
So many absurd words
大人になったって
Even as an adult
愛なんて知らないわ
I don't know what love is
この瞬間オンリー誤魔化す midnight
Faking only this moment, midnight
残されたのは
All that's left is...
ロマンスの果て
The end of romance
受注販売グッズ 0
Made-to-order Goods 0
窓無しの世界は
The windowless world
妙に煌めいてて
Is strangely sparkling
どんな毒を飲ませたら
What kind of poison should I give?
ねえ このまま連れ出してくれぬ
Hey, won't you take me away just like this?
嗤って見せて
Show me a sneer
この隙間 迷って 迷って 狂うのに怯えて
In this gap, wandering, wandering, afraid of going mad
だめ このままじゃ
No, not like this
行かないで
Don't go
足りない 聞かせて今だけは
It's not enough, let me hear it, just for now
祝えカモネ 夜に溺れて
Celebrate, maybe... drowning in the night
無理矢理繰り返す意味なんてないの
抑えられない方程式
Repeating it by force is meaningless,
an uncontrollable equation
やんちゃな放鳥
A mischievous release
先までのヒステリックな街が
The hysteric town until now...
幻想を脱いで煌めき取り戻す
Casts off the illusion and regains its sparkle
Join Us, Be a Starry Starry Jet!
夜空を駆けるストリーミング
Streaming across the night sky
Join Us, Be a Starry Starry Jet!
乗り遅れないでね
Don't miss the ride
Midnight Midnight 心地ええりすぐりの音楽たちを
Midnight Midnight, carefully selected pleasant music
散りばめ Cherry 輝きで満たすよ
Sprinkle it like cherries, I'll fill it with brilliance
地平線 彗星になろうよ
Let's become a comet on the horizon
走り続ける町で
In the town that keeps running
君と彗星になるんだ 盛り上がるの
I'll become a comet with you, let's get excited
Take You Higher 音を通って
Take You Higher, through the sound
パーティーは始まったばかり
The party has just begun
Take You Higher 連れて行くよ
Take You Higher, I'll take you there
さあ一緒に Fly
Now, let's fly together
空落として まぶたの奥 光を追いかける
Casting down the sky, I chase the light behind my eyelids.
消えてしまう前に 覚えておきたくて
Before it all disappears, I want to remember.
ねえ 焦り駆るなんて なぜネガティブなんだっけ
Hey, why am I so negative, driven by impatience?
自問自答 眩い空 状況引き寄せてくる
Self-questioning, the dazzling sky draws the situation in.
Ah! Attention please! お待たせもう Attention please!
Ah! Attention please! Sorry for the wait, attention please!
明日より尊い今日の思い出は
Today's memories are more precious than tomorrow...
Midnight Paint 綺麗だね 君の生き方 綺麗なんだ
Midnight Paint. It's beautiful, the way you live is beautiful.
それぞれが Surely 輝きで満ちてる
Surely, each and every one is filled with brilliance.
今夜彗星になろうよ
Let's become a comet tonight.
君と彗星になるんだ
I'll become a comet with you.
左手で踊る星の一粒さえ この街に欠かせないのなら
If even a single star dancing in my left hand is essential to this city,
そんな今日が本当は好ましいんだな
Then a day like today is actually quite desirable.
どこまでも Party Party Jet
To wherever, Party Party Jet!
どんな夜が明けるまで
Until whatever kind of dawn breaks.
刹那的な Party Party Jet
A momentary Party Party Jet.
まだ終われない
It can't end yet.
燃え上がれ Party Party Jet
Burn bright, Party Party Jet!
朝が来たって忘れない
I won't forget even when morning comes.
最高潮の Party Party Jet
The ultimate Party Party Jet.
さあ 一緒に Fly
Now, let's fly together!
本音も 建前も
True feelings and public facades...
駆け引き上手な大人は 誰だっけ？
Who was the adult so skilled at bargaining?
そんなことお仕置きできない
I can't punish them for that.
便利で 快適で
Convenient and comfortable,
進化し続けるテクノロジー
technology continues to evolve.
伝えて 人肌の温もり
Convey the warmth of human skin.
このままずっと降りやまない雨の世界だ
It's a world where the rain never stops falling.
もう悲しくない 人になれる生き物だから
I'm not sad anymore, because I'm a creature that can become human.
蒼白になった青春の 何ページ目だったっけ
Which page was it in that pale youth of mine?
今君に会いたいと
Right now, I want to see you,
涙込み上げる
and tears start to swell.
飛んだり 跳ねたり 注意散漫人生の転機が
Flying and jumping, a distracted turning point in life...
新しい時代を乗りこなしていくんだ
is riding through a new era.
透明で 鮮明で 叫び声あげる前乗りで
Transparent and vivid, riding ahead before let out a cry...
繋げよ 失敗しては笑ってゆく
Connect it, laughing even as we fail.
このままずっと降りやまない雨の世界だ
It's a world where the rain never stops falling.
愛するしかない それしかない君じゃないから
There's nothing to do but love, because it's not just you.
蒼白になった青春の 何ページ目だったっけ
Which page was it in that pale youth of mine?
忘れ物思い出せないまま
Unable to remember what I've forgotten...
忘れそう このままじゃ
I'm likely to forget if things stay this way.
ヴァイスシュヴァルツ
Weiss Schwarz
ホロライブプロダクションが ヴァイスシュヴァルツに参戦！
Hololive Production joins Weiss Schwarz!
トライアルデッキ＋(プラス) ホロライブプロダクション。好評発売中！
Trial Deck+ Hololive Production. Now on sale!
ブシロード
Bushiroad
D4DJ Groovy Mix。
D4DJ Groovy Mix.
ホロライブ楽曲コラボ開催中だよ！
The Hololive song collaboration is in progress!
ドドーンといろんな楽曲を実装しちゃうんだって！
They're implementing a ton of different songs!
コラボストーリーも...
Collaboration stories too...
「こんぺこ、こんぺこ、こんぺこ〜！ ホロライブ三期生の兎田ぺこらぺこ〜！」
"Konpeko, konpeko, konpeko~! Usada Pekora from Hololive 3rd Gen-peko~!"
...読めちゃう！？
...can be read!?
ゲームBGM、インスト、カバー楽曲も！ DJ気分で遊べちゃう。
Game BGM, instrumentals, and cover songs too! Play with a DJ feel.
繋がろう、グルミクで！
Let's connect in Gurumiku!
ヴァイスシュヴァルツ。
Weiss Schwarz.
ホロライブプロダクションのブースターパックでも、止まらないヴァイスシュヴァルツ！
Even with the Hololive Production booster pack, Weiss Schwarz won't stop!
ブースターパック ホロライブプロダクション。好評発売中！
Booster Pack Hololive Production. Now on sale!
ブシロード
Bushiroad
街を跨ぎ
Crossing the town
風に煽られ
Buffeted by the wind
そしてまた君に会いたいと願い
And wishing to see you again
駆けていく
I'll keep running
だって僕は星だから
Because I am a star
Stellar Stellar
きっと君はもう気づいていた
Surely you've already noticed
僕の心の奥で書いた
What I wrote deep within my heart
それがこれから話す陳腐な
That is the cliché monologue
モノローグさ
I'm about to tell
そっと
Softly
言えない言葉があった
There were words I couldn't say
越せない壁があったんだ
There were walls I couldn't overcome
ずっとさ
Forever
グッと堪りだすあの匂いが
That scent that wells up
どうしようもなく憎らしくて
Is so helplessly hateful
部屋の隅で膝を抱えて
Holding my knees in the corner of the room
震えていた
I was trembling
太陽なんて
Something like the sun
いらないから
I don't need
明けないでいて
So please don't let the day break
その手を伸ばして
Reach out that hand
誰かに届くように
So it reaches someone
僕だって君と同じ
I'm just like you
特別なんかじゃないから
I'm not anyone special
だって僕は夜を歌う
Because I sing of the night
Stellar Stellar ありったけの輝きで
Stellar Stellar, with all the radiance I have
今夜音楽はずっとずっと止まらない
Tonight, the music will never, ever stop
だって僕がずっと泣きたかったのは
Because the reason I wanted to cry all this time
悲しいからじゃないから
Wasn't because I was sad
Stellar Stellar
迎えに行くよさあ
I'm coming to get you, now
だって僕は星だから
Because I am a star
なんてありふれた話なんだ
What a commonplace story
理想だけ書き連ねていた
I just wrote down a list of ideals
ノートの隅に眠る本音は
The true feelings sleeping in the corner of my notebook
きっとあの星も泣いてるんだ
Surely that star is crying too
明日なんて来ないままでいて
Please, don't let tomorrow come
その手を伸ばして
Reach out that hand
誰かに届くように
So it reaches someone
本当に大切なものほど
The things that are truly important
目に見えないみたいなんだ
Seem to be invisible to the eye
だって僕は夜を歌う
Because I sing of the night
Stellar Stellar ありのまま輝いて
Stellar Stellar, shining just as you are
今夜音楽はきっときっと止まらない
Tonight, the music will surely, surely never stop
だって僕がずっと泣きたかったのは
Because the reason I wanted to cry all this time
明日輝くためじゃないかな
Might be so that I can shine tomorrow
Stellar Stellar
迎えに行くよさあ
I'm coming to get you, now
僕だって星だから
Because I am a star too
本日は、星街すいせい 1st Solo Live 「STELLAR into the GALAXY」 Supported By Bushiroad へお越しいただき...
Thank you for coming to Hoshimachi Suisei 1st Solo Live "STELLAR into the GALAXY" Supported By Bushiroad today...
Hoshimachi Suisei 1st Solo Live “STELLAR into the GALAXY” Supported by Bushiroadにご来場いただきまして、誠にありがとうございます。
Thank you very much for coming to Hoshimachi Suisei 1st Solo Live "STELLAR into the GALAXY" Supported by Bushiroad.
記念すべきわたくし、星街すいせいの1stソロライブを楽しみにしてくださっている皆さん、本日はどうぞよろしくお願いいたします。
To everyone who has been looking forward to my commemorative first solo live, thank you for being here today.
さて、公演を最後まで楽しんでいただくために、皆様へいくつかご案内をさせてください。
Now, to ensure everyone enjoys the performance until the end, please let me give you a few announcements.
まず始めに、ロビー客席内ではマスク着用必須になりますので、マスクのご持参をお願いいたします。
First, masks are mandatory in the lobby and seating areas, so please make sure to bring one.
公演中の掛け声、声援は、新型コロナウイルス感染予防の視点からご遠慮ください。
Please refrain from shouting or cheering during the performance to prevent the spread of COVID-19.
ぜひ拍手での応援をお願いいたします。
We ask for your support through clapping instead.
また、会場内では係員の指示に従ってください。
Also, please follow the instructions of the staff inside the venue.
客席内でのモッシュ、ダイブ、ジャンプ等の危険行為、ルールに反したコンサートライトの使用は禁止となります。
Dangerous acts such as moshing, diving, and jumping, and the use of concert lights against the rules are prohibited.
これらの行為を守れない場合、公演が中断する場合もございますので、ご理解とご協力をお願いいたします。
If these rules are not followed, the performance may be interrupted. We appreciate your understanding and cooperation.
このほか、会場内では携帯はマナーモードにしていただきますようお願い申し上げます。
In addition, please keep your mobile phones on silent mode within the venue.
本公演は映像配信および写真撮影用のカメラが会場内に入り、客席のお客様の様子が映り込む場合がございます。
This performance will be filmed and photographed, and there is a possibility that audience members may be captured.
これらの映像や写真はプロモーション等に使用される可能性がございますので、あらかじめご了承ください。
Please be aware that these videos and photos may be used for promotional purposes.
ペンライトは周りのお客様のご迷惑にならないよう、ご配慮をお願いいたします。
Please be considerate of the customers around you when using penlights.
頭の上に出したり、大きく左右に振り回されますと、後ろのお客様や周りのお客様のご迷惑となる場合がございます。
Holding them above your head or swinging them widely may disturb the customers behind or around you.
係の者が注意させていただく場合がございますので、ご了承ください。
Please note that staff members may issue a warning.
続いて、注意事項をお伝えします。
Next, I would like to convey some precautions.
本ライブの録音、録画、ミラー配信や違法アップロードは、固くお断りいたします。
Recording, filming, mirror streaming, or illegal uploading of this live performance is strictly prohibited.
また、会場現地で本番中のライブの様子を撮影することは、演出の都合上、禁止とさせていただきます。
Also, taking photos or videos of the live performance at the venue during the show is prohibited for production reasons.
何卒ご了承ください。
Thank you for your understanding.
ただし、配信でご覧いただいている皆様におきましては、スクリーンショットを撮影いただき、SNSで画像付きで感想を投稿いただくことは歓迎します。
However, for those watching via streaming, you are welcome to take screenshots and post your impressions on SNS with images.
本公演のハッシュタグは、「#かがやく星街」です。
The hashtag for this performance is "#かがやく星街".
ぜひハッシュタグを使ってライブを盛り上げてください。
Please use the hashtag to liven up the live performance!
また、ライブ配信について、データ通信量が多くなることが想定されるため、スマートフォンでご覧になる場合には、Wi-Fiでのご利用を推奨いたします。
Regarding the live stream, data usage is expected to be high, so we recommend using Wi-Fi if you are watching on a smartphone.
インターネット回線の接続が不安定な場合は、配信動画のクオリティを保証できません。
If your internet connection is unstable, we cannot guarantee the quality of the streamed video.
最善の準備を行いライブ配信を実施いたしますが、
We will do our best to prepare and conduct the live stream, but...
生配信の特性上、不慮の障害で映像の乱れや一時停止等が起こる可能性があります。
Due to the nature of live streaming, there is a possibility of video distortion or temporary pauses due to unexpected issues.
あらかじめご了承ください。
Thank you for your understanding in advance.
終演後は、規制退場を行います。
After the performance, we will conduct a regulated exit.
席の方でスタッフの指示があるまでお待ちください。
Please wait at your seat until you receive instructions from the staff.
以上のことが守られない場合、安全確保のため、公演を一時中断、もしくは中止させていただくこともございますので、あらかじめご了承ください。
If the above rules are not followed, the performance may be suspended or cancelled for safety reasons.
最後に、ご気分のすぐれない場合など、何かございましたら、お早めにお近くのスタッフにお申し付けください。
Finally, if you feel unwell, please let a nearby staff member know as soon as possible.
また、地震などの緊急時にはスタッフが誘導いたします。
In case of an emergency such as an earthquake, the staff will guide you.
スタッフの指示があるまで、お席にてお待ちくださいますよう、お願いいたします。
Please wait at your seats until further instructions from the staff.
さて、わたくしからのご案内は以上となります。
Well, that's all for the announcements from me.
開演まであと少し。皆さん、ライブに向けた準備はできていますか？
Just a little longer until the start. Everyone, are you ready for the live?
ライトの電池は入っていますか？
Are the batteries in your lights?
タオルは手元にお持ちですか？
Do you have your towels ready?
Tシャツ着てますか？
Are you wearing your T-shirts?
声は出しちゃダメですよ！
Don't shout out loud!
声を出さず、声援なしで、心の中で叫んでみてください。
Without using your voice or cheering, please try shouting in your heart.
配信の方たちとかは、ご近所さん、またはお母さんにご配慮の上、叫んでください。
For those watching the stream, please shout while being considerate of your neighbors or your mother.
それでは、開演まで今しばらくお待ちください。星街すいせいでした。
Well then, please wait a little longer until the show starts. This was Hoshimachi Suisei.
Flower Stand
フラワースタンド紹介
Introduction
はじまりはそうよ
Yes, it's the beginning
世界は変わるから
Because the world will change
明日は晴れるから
Because tomorrow will be sunny
Hoshimachi Suisei 1st Solo Live “STELLAR into the GALAXY”
開演までしばらくお待ちください
SNSでの感想投稿OK
Hoshimachi Suisei 1st Solo Live “STELLAR into the GALAXY”
The show will start shortly. Please wait for a while.
Posting impressions on SNS is OK
本日は、星街すいせい 1st Solo Live “STELLAR into the GALAXY” Supported By Bushiroadにご来場いただきまして、誠にありがとうございます。
Thank you very much for attending Hoshimachi Suisei 1st Solo Live “STELLAR into the GALAXY” Supported By Bushiroad today.
大変長らくお待たせいたしました。
Thank you for waiting so long.
本公演は間もなく開演いたします。
The performance will begin shortly.
みなさん、一緒に盛り上がる準備はできてますか？
Are you all ready to get excited together?
ペンライトと拍手で応えてください！
Please respond with your penlights and applause!
最後まで一緒に楽しみましょう！
Let's enjoy it together until the end!
あらためまして、
Once again,
星街すいせいファーストソロライブ、
Hoshimachi Suisei 1st Solo Live,
“STELLAR into the GALAXY”
Supported By Bushiroad、
Supported By Bushiroad,
開演します！
will now begin!
スタート！
Start!
誰もが、この街で孤独だった。
Everyone was lonely in this city.
道行く人々はすれ違い、
People pass each other on the streets,
思い描く未来も霞がかっている。
and the future they imagine is clouded.
空で輝いているはずの星は、
The stars that should be shining in the sky
雲に覆われて見えない。
are covered by clouds and cannot be seen.
そして僕は、
And I,
今日も何者にもなれないでいる。
still haven't become anyone today.
アッとはじけた感情に
At my suddenly burst emotions,
言い訳を並べて過ごした
I spent my time lining up excuses.
葛藤も知らない街明かり
The city lights that know no conflict,
君だけだった、そう見えた
it was only you, or so it seemed.
信じたくもないままで、踊っている
Without even wanting to believe, I'm dancing.
示し合わずに、連ね続けた言葉
Without any sign, words kept on following.
見えないの？僕が
Can't you see me?
僕のこの声が聞こえてる？
Can you hear this voice of mine?
断罪したシルエットすらも
Even the condemned silhouette
透明できっと、不格好だけど
is transparent and surely awkward, but
でも、せめて声を枯らそう
at least, I'll scream my voice out.
必死にすがってもずっと照明を
Even if I cling desperately, always
焦がすほどみたいだ
it seems like it's burning the lights.
散々恨んだ明るさと
With the brightness I hated so much,
意味ありげに伸びてゆく影
and the shadows stretching out meaningfully.
淡々と過ぎたひとつぶの
A single drop passed indifferently,
君の言葉で歩きたくなった
your words made me want to walk.
大切にしたいものが、こぼれてゆく
Things I want to cherish are spilling away.
示し様に、綴り続けたい言葉
In a way to show, words I want to keep writing.
見えてるの？僕が
Can you see me?
僕のこの声が届いてる？
Is this voice of mine reaching you?
断罪したシルエットすらも
Even the condemned silhouette...
透明できっと不恰好だけれど
Translucent and surely ungraceful,
でも
But...
だから叫んで 喘いで
That's why I'm screaming, struggling,
裸足のまま走ってね
Running barefoot.
気付いて教えてよ
Please notice and tell me,
答えは
The answer is...
こんな
Like this,
僕の心まで透明にしないで
Please don't make even my heart transparent.
灰色の街が笑ってる
The grey city is laughing,
足取り重くなる
My footsteps are getting heavy.
声を枯らして叫んで喘いで裸足で走り続けて
With a withered voice, screaming, struggling, continuing to run barefoot,
変わらないように
So that nothing changes,
諦めないように
So that I don't give up,
爪を立て続けるだけだ
I'll just keep digging my claws in.
見つけてよ僕を
Please find me,
僕の声が聞こえてる
Can you hear my voice?
残像 雑踏 シルエットすらも
Afterimages, crowds, even the silhouettes,
透明できっと不恰好だけれどでも
Are translucent and surely ungraceful, but...
せめて声を枯らそう
At least I'll let my voice wither away,
必死に縋って求めて
Clinging desperately, seeking,
そばに願う姿見たいんだ
I want to see the figure I wish to be beside me.
Stellar Stellar!
もっともっと！
More, more!
本音も建前も 駆け引き上手な大人はダメね
True feelings and pretenses, adults good at bargaining are no good, right?
そんな言葉使用できない できない
Those kinds of words, I can't use them, I can't.
便利で快適で進化し続けてるテクノロジー
Convenient, comfortable, and ever-evolving technology,
伝えて人肌の温もり
Convey the warmth of human skin.
ねえこのままずっと降り止まない雨の世界だ
Hey, it's a world of rain that won't stop falling like this forever,
もう悲しくない 人はなれる生き物だから
I'm not sad anymore, because humans are creatures that can adapt.
総白になった青春の1ページ目だっけ
Was it the first page of my youth that turned completely white?
今君に会いたいと涙込み上げる
Now I want to see you, and tears well up.
踏んだり蹴ったり注意散漫人生の天気が
Ups and downs, distracted, the weather of life is...
嵐 新しい時代を乗りこなして行くんだ
A storm, I'm going to master this new era.
透明で鮮明で叫び声上げるマイノリティ
Translucent and vivid, a minority raising a scream,
失敗しては笑ってく
Laughing as I fail.
もうこのままずっと降り止まない雨の世界だ
Already, it's a world of rain that won't stop falling like this forever,
愛するしかない それしかない器用じゃないから
I have no choice but to love, that's all there is, because I'm not clever enough.
総白になった青春の1ページ目だっけ
Was it the first page of my youth that turned completely white?
忘れ物思い出せないまま忘れそう
I'm about to forget the things I lost without being able to remember them,
このままじゃ
If things stay like this...
風の形見えない 見えないよあなたが
The shape of the wind is invisible, I can't see you,
あなただって同じ じっとしてられない
You're the same, you can't stay still.
動き出すよ この身駆けて 降参ないよ
I'll start moving, putting my life on the line, I won't surrender,
泣いたってしょうがないさ
It's no use crying.
ねえこのままずっと降り止まない雨の世界だ
Hey, it's a world of rain that won't stop falling like this forever,
もう悲しくない 人はなれる生き物だから
I'm not sad anymore, because humans are creatures that can adapt.
総白になった青春の
Of my youth that turned completely white...
...なんページ目だったっけ
...What page was it on again?
今君に会いたいと
Now, wanting to see you
涙こらえて
Holding back my tears
さよならだ さよならなんだって 認めたくないけど
It's goodbye, even if I don't want to admit it's goodbye
雨上がりの この世界が 眩しいから
Because this world after the rain is so dazzling
もう帰れない 振り返らない 思い出と共に
I can't go back anymore, I won't look back, together with my memories
新しい風にあおられ
Buffeted by a new wind
そしてまた 君に会いたいと願い 駆けていく
And so again, wishing to see you, I run on
駆けていく
I run on
葛藤のサイレン 乾いた戦場
The siren of conflict, a parched battlefield
生け捕りつけた 引き分けは3.2リッター
A captured draw, 3.2 liters
どんな言葉にもちゃんと ほころびがあった
Every word had its cracks
もう何も言わずに遊ぼう
Let's just play without saying anything more
どうでもいい朝に 誰一人聞いて
On a trivial morning, with no one listening
傘は持ってない 借りてた未来
I don't have an umbrella, a borrowed future
貸し借し欠かし空から 街ゆく余所者の
Lending, borrowing, lacking, from the sky, a stranger in the city
ねぇねぇ一人だ 片手離したのはベイビー レイニー
Hey, hey, I'm alone, the one who let go of your hand was baby, Rainy
レイニー 君は隣にいないんだね
Rainy, you're not by my side, are you?
悲しくはないよ 嬉しくもないよベイビー レイニー
I'm not sad, but I'm not happy either, baby, Rainy
レイニー 欲を言えば隣に
Rainy, if I were to ask for more, by my side
現世式の塗装を 染めるレイニー レイニー
Staining the mundane paint, Rainy, Rainy
レイニー この街を変えたんだね
Rainy, you changed this town, didn't you?
レプリカステップ パノラマ レイニー レイニー
Replica step, panorama, Rainy, Rainy
レイニー 君はなんて言ったの
Rainy, what did you say?
バイバイ バイバイ 欲を言えば隣に 証拠
Bye-bye, bye-bye, if I were to ask for more, by my side, evidence
臭いのアトラクション あやってワンウェイテール
A smelly attraction, manipulated one-way tail
光あたれば それでよかった
If the light shone, that was enough
会えないと 会えないと 泣いた後の事
The things after crying because we can't meet, we can't meet
再生のよは 混ざりたくないな
I don't want to mix with the world of rebirth
幻想 5分の
Fantasy, five minutes
砂地声 宇宙の裏
A sandy voice, the back of the universe
白い煙に吹かれながら歌う
Singing while being blown by white smoke
救いもない 四迷琴
No salvation, a world of confusion
ねぇねぇ一人だ こぼしたのはベイビー レイニー
Hey, hey, I'm alone, the one who spilled it was baby, Rainy
レイニー 空を見たいだけ
Rainy, I just want to see the sky
確かな声に 似ているアリバイ バイバイ バイバイ
An alibi that resembles a certain voice, bye-bye, bye-bye
バイバイ しなくちゃいけないんだ
Bye-bye, I have to do it
歩道のかすも ありのなりなり
Even the dregs of the sidewalk, as they are
君も行くなら 虹を祈ってる
If you're going too, I'll pray for a rainbow
ねぇねぇ一人だ 片手離したのはベイビー レイニー
Hey, hey, I'm alone, the one who let go of your hand was baby, Rainy
レイニー 君は隣にいないんだね
Rainy, you're not by my side, are you?
悲しくはないよ 嬉しくもないよベイビー レイニー
I'm not sad, but I'm not happy either, baby, Rainy
レイニー 欲を言えば隣に
Rainy, if I were to ask for more, by my side
現世式の塗装を 埋めるレイニー レイニー
Filling in the mundane paint, Rainy, Rainy
レイニー 触れたかったんだよね
Rainy, I wanted to touch you, didn't I?
レプリカステップ パノラマ レイニー レイニー
Replica step, panorama, Rainy, Rainy
レイニー 君を待っていたよ
Rainy, I was waiting for you
バイバイ バイバイ 欲を言えば隣で バイバイ
Bye-bye, bye-bye, if I were to ask for more, by my side, bye-bye
はい、ありがとうございましたー！
Yes, thank you very much!
ふー、まずはね、3曲歌わせていただきました！
Whew, first, I sang three songs!
ふー、いや、今日めっちゃ寒くてさ、
Whew, man, it's really cold today,
なんか、寒すぎて舞台袖にいる時から、
It was so cold that even while I was in the wings,
寒い寒い寒い！って。
I was like, "It's cold, it's cold, it's cold!"
寄せてたんですけど、
I was planning to, but...
ステージに出てきたらだいぶ熱いです。
...coming out on stage, it's pretty hot.
はい、ということで、最初の挨拶からいきたいと思います。
Yes, and so, I'd like to start with my first greeting.
最初の挨拶と言ったらね、
Speaking of the first greeting...
この場所にいる皆さんは声を出したいあれがあると思うんですけど、
...I'm sure everyone here has that thing they want to shout out,
声を出せないと思うので、今日は...ペンライトでね、
but since you can't shout today... let's use penlights instead.
「今日も可愛い！」で、「今日も可愛い！」でいきましょう。
Let's go with "Kyou mo Kawaii!" (You're cute today too!).
続いていきましょう。じゃあいきますよ。
Let's do that. Okay, here we go.
彗星の如く現れたスターの原石！
The star's rough diamond that appeared like a comet!
アイドルVTuberの星街すいせいです！
I'm the idol VTuber, Hoshimachi Suisei!
すいちゃんはー？
Sui-chan wa—?
あー、分かる、分かる。あ、すごい分かる！すごい分かる！
Ah, I can tell, I can tell. Oh, I can totally tell! I can totally tell!
あー、いいですね。「今日も可愛い」聞こえてきました。ありがとうございます。
Ah, that's great. I could hear "Kyou mo Kawaii". Thank you very much.
ということで、星街すいせい 1stソロライブ
And so, welcome to Hoshimachi Suisei 1st Solo Live
“STELLAR into the GALAXY” Supported By Bushiroad へようこそ！
"STELLAR into the GALAXY" Supported By Bushiroad!
いやー、念願のね、1stソロライブ！
Wow, the long-awaited 1st solo live!
しかも豊洲PITということで、本当にこの日を待ち望んで、
And at Toyosu PIT, too. I've really been looking forward to this day,
もう何ヶ月も準備をして参りましたが、
and have been preparing for months.
皆さん今どうですか？楽しいですか？
How is everyone feeling now? Are you having fun?
わー、ありがとう！いやあのさ、
Wow, thank you! You know,
いやなんかさっきモニターで見てたんだけど、
I was watching on the monitor earlier,
なんかね最前列のところらへんの人が椅子に、なんか分からないけどぬいぐるみを、
and the people near the front row had plushies on their chairs, I'm not sure why,
ぬいぐるみか何か置いてて、「なんだこのぬいぐるみは！？」ってなってたのを見てました。
they placed plushies or something, and I was thinking, "What are these plushies!?"
あとね、あの、男性も女性もなんかもう半分半分くらいじゃないですか？だいぶ。
Also, it looks like it's about half men and half women, doesn't it?
はい、男性の人挙手！
Okay, men, raise your hands!
いっぱーい！
So many!
はい、女性の人挙手！
Okay, women, raise your hands!
あ、いっぱーい！
Ah, so many!
嬉しい。えー、老若男女に人気な星街すいせいということでね。
I'm happy. Hoshimachi Suisei is popular with people of all ages and genders.
あのー、やっぱりね、皆さんの声がないと、あの受けてるのか受けてないのか分かりませんね。
Well, as I thought, without your voices, I can't tell if you're enjoying it or not.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
きっと今ね、受けてるでしょう。あ、そしてね、あのー、
I'm sure you're enjoying it now. Oh, and also,
ちょっと電波を受信することができてですね、あの、コメントを、コメントを読めるんですよ。
I can receive signals now, so I can read comments!
なんて？「はい」「草」「パチパチ」
What's it say? "Yes", "Kusa" (lol), "Clap clap",
「可愛いよ」みたいな、いっぱいちょっとね、見えます。
"You're cute"... I can see lots of them.
電波を受信できます。ありがとう、配信の皆さんも！ありがとう！
I can receive the signals. Thank you to everyone on the stream too! Thank you!
いやー楽しいね、もうなんか楽しいわ。もう楽しい。
Man, this is fun. I'm already having fun. So much fun.
はい、配信で見てくださってる皆さん、ハッシュタグ「#輝く星街」でたくさん呟いてください。
For those watching the stream, please tweet using the hashtag #輝く星街 (Shining Suisei).
なんかもうトレンド1位になったっていう話題が出たんですけど、
I heard we've already reached #1 on trending.
本当ですか？本当ですか？
Is it true? Is it true?
やったー！ありがとう！
Yay! Thank you!
会場の皆さんはね、ぜひ呟けない分たくさんペンライト振ってください。
For everyone at the venue, please wave your penlights a lot since you can't tweet.
ホイホイホイホイホイ...
Hoi hoi hoi hoi hoi...
はい、じゃあね。ライブタイトルにもね、あります通り、
Okay, then. As it says in the live title,
今回のライブはブシロードさんにご協賛をいただいております！
this live is sponsored by Bushiroad!
ブシロードさん、ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much, Bushiroad!
今ね、見えてるかな？上のLEDにコラボ情報が映ってるかなと思います。
Can you see it? I think the LED above is showing collaboration info.
まずは、トレーディングカードゲーム『ヴァイスシュヴァルツ』より、『ホロライブプロダクション』のパックが好評発売中です。
First, from the card game "Weiß Schwarz", "Hololive Production" packs are now on sale.
私の箔押しサインカードも入ってるらしいよ。
Apparently, they include my foil-stamped autograph cards.
入手困難らしいよ、これ。
I heard they're hard to get.
ぜひね、詳細はヴァイスシュヴァルツ公式サイトをチェックしてみてください。
Please check the official Weiß Schwarz website for details.
さらに、スマートフォン向けリズムゲーム『D4DJ Groovy Mix』が、もうすぐ1周年ということで、
Furthermore, the rhythm game "D4DJ Groovy Mix" is almost at its 1st anniversary,
ホロライブコラボガチャも復刻するみたいです！やったー！
and the Hololive collaboration gacha will be returning! Yay!
さらに！星街すいせいの「Stellar Stellar」が
Moreover! Hoshimachi Suisei's "Stellar Stellar"...
このライブの後、すぐ実装されちゃいます！やったー！
...will be added to the game right after this live! Yay!
私のカードイラストもゲームを遊ぶだけでゲットできちゃいますので、ぜひぜひダウンロードしてみてくださいね。
You can also get my card illustration just by playing the game, so please download it.
というダイマを挟んだところで、
Now that the self-promotion is over,
YouTubeでご覧の皆さんはここでお別れとなってしまいます。
it's time to say goodbye to everyone watching on YouTube.
いやー寂しい！あ、寂しいの拍手お願いします。
Oh, how sad! Ah, please clap for how sad it is.
ありがとうございます。今ね、YouTubeでチラ見せ配信をしているんですけれども、
Thank you. We're currently doing a "sneak peek" stream on YouTube,
もうね、チラ見せ終わりということで、あの、ぜひ続きが見たいなと思った方は、
but the sneak peek is coming to an end. If you'd like to see the rest...
S-P-W-Nと書いて『スポーン』って読むんですけど、
It's written S-P-W-N and pronounced "SPWN",
スポーンにて続きが見れますので、ぜひ概要欄をチェックしてみてください。
but you can watch the rest on SPWN, so please check the description.
下？
Down?
多分下。
Probably down.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
謎拍手ありがとう。助かります。
Thank you for the mysterious applause. It helps.
はい、ライブはまだまだこれからです。
Yes, the live is still just beginning.
ゲストとのデュエットや、いろんな演出がね、たくさんありますので、
There will be duets with guests and many different performances,
後悔しないように、ぜひ今のうちに買ってくださいね。
so please buy it now so you don't regret it.
「お水など飲みながら」って書いてあるんで、お水飲みます。
It says "while drinking water", so I'll drink some water.
お水見えました？今。
Did you see the water just now?
お水見えました？
Did you see the water?
これね、星詠みには見えないお水なんです。
This water is invisible to Hoshiyomi.
星詠みじゃない人には、お水が見えるかもしれない。
People who aren't Hoshiyomi might be able to see it.
ということでね、あの、このマイクをちょっと今から置きたいと思います。
So, I'm going to put this mic down now.
いきますよ。
Here I go.
マイク置くのに、いきますよ！
I'm going to put the mic down, here I go!
いきますよ！いきますよ！
Here I go! Here I go!
パッ！
Ta-da!
はい、ない！
Look, it's gone!
はい、はい、はい。
Yes, yes, yes.
じゃあね、まだまだたくさん歌いたい曲がありますんで、
Now then, there are still many songs I want to sing,
早速、次の曲にいきたいと思います。
so I'd like to move on to the next song right away.
最後まで盛り上がっていきましょう！
Let's keep the excitement going until the end!
無料パートは終了いたしました
The free portion has ended
ご視聴ありがとうございました！
Thank you for watching!
無料パートは終了いたしました
The free part has ended.
ご視聴ありがとうございました！
Thank you for watching!